DHR&Hakugetsu Sub
翻譯：モビイ•ディック CRF 因果律 果妹子  後期：水姬、KoU
Thank you for this meal.
いただきます
- Thank you for this meal.
Thank you for this meal.
いただきます
Nemurenai yoru ni kiita monogatari ga
What if the story I heard that sleepless night
esoragoto da to shitara
was all just an impossible dream?
Eien wo shiru yori kairaku wo motomete
What if I pursue pleasure, and lament the moment
ima wo kuyande shimau no wa
instead of learning about the eternities
kokoro no fukaku ni sumitsuita kage kara
so that I can escape from the shadows
nigeru tame da to shitara
that dwell deep within my heart?
Sore demo atashi wa atashi wa ai shite irareru nara
But even so, as long as I, as long as I can still keep loving
Hanbun ni wareta taiyou ga asa wo tsurete kite
The sun split in half brings with it the morning
yami ni nareta shinkei wo jiwari shigeki suru
gradually stimulating my nerves, so used to the darkness
Okiwasureta ano ai wa aete sono mama de
I'll dare to leave the love that I'd misplaced as it is
Shinario no kieta monogatari wa
A story whose plot has been erased,
jiyuu ni jiyuu ni kaji wo totte
freely, freely, takes the helm,
motto takaku e maiagatte
soaring ever higher
礼弥が　ゾンビになってから
Ever since Rea became a zombie,
I've started keeping
observational records of her.
俺は　礼弥の観察記録を
撮るようになった
This is something critical, at all times...
"Counterfeit... Freedom..."
This is something critical, at all times.
それは　いつ何時でも
欠かせない
Geez, when we're eating, at least,
you don't have to record me, do you?
もう　お食事のときくらい
撮らなくてもいいじゃないですか
What are you talking about?
何言ってんだよ
それじゃ観察記録にならないだろ
Then it wouldn't be an
observational record, would it?
Yes, that's true, but...
それは　そうですけど
See? So just eat normally.
だろ？　だから普通に食事する
O-Okay...
Hey, Chihiro...
コラ　千紘
You're the one who
isn't eating as usual, right?
ちゃんと食事をしていないのは
お前の方だろ　いい加減にせんか
Knock it off, already.
'kay...
は～い
Rea, you're a vegetarian, are you?
礼弥ちゃんは
ベジタリアンなんだね
Y-Yes...
あッ　はい
No...!
Why?! How come there
are mud snails in the miso soup?!
なぜ　どうして味噌汁の具が
タニシなのだ
じーじ　それはしじみだが
Gramps, those are shijimi clams.
えッ　え～　そうか？
They are?
Oh...
おや
うふふふ…
There are a number of things I've learned
礼弥の証言などから
いくつか分かったことがある
from Rea's statements and whatnot.
First, zombies do not seem to require sleep.
まず　ゾンビは
睡眠をとらなくていいようだ
While on the one hand,
it makes for efficient use of their time,
時間が有意義に使える反面
俺とかは　普通に寝てしまうので
結構退屈なのだそうだ
others, like me, have to sleep,
and she says that gets pretty boring.
While she does shower, she does not sweat.
シャワーは浴びるが
汗はかかない
あと…
Also...
...she says she doesn't make bodily waste.
排泄もしないのだそうだ
蘇生薬の効果持続のために
Owing to the duration
of the reanimation drug,
she has to eat hydrangea
leaves every few hours.
数時間おきに
あじさいの葉を食べているが…
ぬわ～
Babu coughed up the ball
of hydrangea leaves he had eaten,
ばーぶが　まるで胃にたまった
毛玉を吐き出すように
almost like he was coughing
up a hairball out of his stomach,
食べたあじさいを丸めて
吐き出していたので
so Rea will probably do the same thing...
たぶん礼弥も同じことを…
If that's true,
I'd sure like to capture that moment!
もし　そうなら
その瞬間を収めたいな～
フッフフフ～
Say, is anything going
to be coming out of your mouth?
ねえねえ
何か口から出ない？
What are you expecting?
何を期待してるんですか
フッフ～ン
W-Well, in exchange
for letting you record me,
じゃ　じゃあ
私を撮ってもいい代わりに
you'll do something
that I ask you to do, right?
私の言うことも
聞いてくれますよね
うん？
普通の女の子のすることです
Something that normal girls do.
That being...?
というと？
Look, Furuya!
ねえ　降谷君
これはどうですか？
How do you like this one?
Huh? Yeah, that's good, I guess.
うん？　う～ん
それでいいんじゃね
Oh, Furuya! Would you
please take this more seriously?
もう降谷君
もっと真剣に見てください
I don't often get to choose clothes.
せっかくお洋服選びしてるのに
Yeah, but still,
いや　つってもさ　お前
さっきから　なかなか決めねえし
you haven't been able to
decide on anything for a good while.
Well, you are going
to buy it for me, after all.
だって　せっかく降谷君が
買ってくれるんですもの
I want to pick something
that's at least somewhat good.
少しでも
いいものを選びたいんです
But this has already taken an hour.
でも　もう
１時間くらい回ってんだぞ
Ah! Is it okay if I buy a hat, too?
あッ　お帽子も
買っていいですか？
Sure. Just keep the total under ¥10,000.
いいけど　合計１万円以内な
俺の小遣いが
So much for my allowance...
It's cloudy out, so it's not a problem,
曇ってるから　まだいいけど
but being out in the sun like this...
こんな日中に外出なんて
...is going to make her
body spoil that much quicker.
体の傷みが
早まっちまうってのにさ
That's how badly she wants to go shopping.
そこまでして買い物したいんだ
There's no point in
recording her here, is there?
こんなとこ撮っても
意味ねえんじゃ…
お別れ会で流れる
ビデオじゃないんだし
This isn't some video I'm playing
at a farewell party, after all.
Yes, I think that color
looks very good on you, miss.
ええ　ですからお客様には
その色がお似合いだと思うんです
See? It really does go well.
ほら　やっぱりいいですよ
アハッ
But then, yeah...
でも　そっか
I'm sure that Rea hasn't
been allowed to do this before,
礼弥は　きっと
こんな当たり前のことも
stuff that is only natural for girls to do.
これまで
させてもらえなかったんだよな
今日はいつもより
ゆっくり入るか
I think I'll stay in longer than usual today.
Ah... that's bracing...
はあ～　しみるわ
う～んふ
The bathhouse in the middle
of the day sure is great!
真っ昼間の銭湯って
やっぱいいよね
But then again...
とは　いったものの…
I have to take "responsibility" for her.
俺　あいつの責任をとる
必要があるんだ
"The water's fine..." isn't true, huh?
いい湯
じゃないな～
I've never seen Chihiro look so serious.
あんな真面目な千紘
初めて見た
I know the fact that
Miss Sanka has become a zombie
散華さんが
ゾンビになってしまった事情は
色々あるんだろうけど
does mean a lot...
だからって
But even so, for him
to suddenly start living with her,
私には何も言わないで
いきなり同棲とかさ…
without even saying anything to me...
And I've put on some weight.
ちょっと太ったし
Man!
もう！　まったく
For crying out loud,
it's always Rea this, Rea that!
いっつもいっつも
礼弥さん礼弥さんって
"Women"
Can't he at least think about me a little...
ちょっとは私のことぐらい…
あッ
あッ　こんにちは
Ah, hello.
Wah! Mero!
わあ　萌路ちゃん
アハハハハ　奇遇ね
What a coincidence, huh?
Hi there.
どもでっす
Hi.
どうも
ウッフフフ
Excuse us.
失礼します～
Lady Wanko, you're visiting
the bathhouse at midday, too?
わんこ殿も昼間から銭湯で？
M-Mm-hmm...
う　うん　午前中に
ウチの手伝い終わったから
I needed a change of pace
after helping out at home all morning.
気分転換にさ
ハハッ　ハハハハ　ハッ
So, Mero, are you grabbing
a quick bath with your friends?
…って　萌路ちゃんも
友達とひとっ風呂？
Or are you on the way home
from being out somewhere?
それとも　どこか出かけた帰り？
No, we thought we'd visit the
bathhouse instead of going for tea.
いや　お茶する代わりに
銭湯に入ろうかと
あ～　あッ　そういえば
千紘って今　家にいる？
Come to think of it,
is Chihiro at home right now?
Oh, Brother left for the shopping center
あッ　にーは朝から
隣町の
ショッピングセンターに行きましたぞ→
in the next town over this morning.
He said he was buying clothes for Lady Rea.
礼弥殿の服を買うとかで
Hmm... The two of them
are enjoying themselves...
ふ～ん　二人で楽しんでるんだ
All right!
よ～しッ
もっかい萌路ちゃん達と
風呂入っちゃる～
I'm gonna hop in the bath
once again, together with you guys!
We'll drown our troubles in the bath!
ヤケ風呂だ～
三人とも夕方まで付き合え
All three of us!
Stick with me until this evening!
うりゃ～！
ハハハ　ハハハハハッ
The hot water is going to your head.
湯あたりしますぞ
Sorry to keep you waiting, Furuya!
お待たせしました　降谷君
You look good...
似合ってんじゃん
Hmm? What did you just say?
うん？　今
何て言いました？
I didn't say anything.
何も言ってねえよ
Eh? Yes you did.
えッ？　言いましたよ
No I didn't.
言ってねえって
You did so. Please, say it one more time.
言いました
もう一回　言ってみてくださいよ
あれ？
降谷君も何か買ったんですか？
Huh?
Furuya, did you buy something, too?
Huh? Yeah...
Oh, yeah? What is it? Can I have a look?
へえ～　何ですか？
見せてもらっても…
Aw, do I have to?
まあ　いいじゃんかよ
ふ～ん
Ah, so where should we go next?
それで次は
どこ行きましょうか
You still want to look around?
まだ見て回んのかよ
はい　まだまだ見て回りますよ
Yes! I still want to go looking around!
I have something to report.
ご報告します
Target is currently at
a shopping center in town.
ターゲットは現在
市内のショッピングセンターにいます
例の降谷と二人だけのようです
She appears to be alone with
that Furuya boy. What shall I do?
いかがいたしましょうか
Hmm, all right.
Continue your surveillance as before.
ふむ　分かった
これまでどおり監視を続けておけ
あれ　入ってもいいですか？
Ah, over there! Can we go in there?
There is no need to rush this.
焦る必要はない
Bide your time.
時を待つのだ
Then, when Rea is by herself...
そして礼弥が
一人きりになったら…
...execute!
決行しろ
As you wish.
かしこまりました
This is really well-made, though
some of the rough edges stand out.
大変よくできていますね
でも　ちょっと
粗さが目立ちます
特に　この縫い方は
The way this is stitched
together here in particular
もう少し丁寧にされた方が
よりいいと思いますよ
would have been better had it
been more neatly done, if you ask me.
Don't you think so, Furuya...
ねッ　降谷君もそう…
Huh?
あれ？
"Cursed Horror House"
You're kidding, Furuya!
I never would have imagined
まさか降谷君
お化け屋敷が苦手だったなんて
that you couldn't
handle a haunted house!
思いもしませんでした
Sh-Shut up. Is that wrong?
うるせッ　悪いかよ
ゾンビとか
ホラー映画が好きなのと
Me liking zombies and horror movies
is a lot different from that type of thing.
ああいう系は別物だっての
へえ～　そうなんですか
Oh, yeah? You don't say.
And as for you,
つうか　お前さ
you don't have to be so good at everything...
何だかんだで結構強い…
W-What, are you making fun of me?
何だよ　バカにしてんのか
アハハハ　それでも私のために
一緒に入って…　くれたんだ？
And despite it all,
you still went in there... for me.
Thank you, Furuya.
ありがとうね　降谷君
Well, I'm not going in the next one!
まッ　次は入んねえけどな
Okay.
はい
あッ　あとさ
Oh, yeah...
Here.
これ
うん？
It's going to get a
lot hotter from here on out.
これから　どんどん暑くなるからさ
If you put dry ice in
here and wear it around,
これにドライアイス仕込んで着れば
体が傷むのも抑えられて
it will help keep your body from decaying,
and I think it will make it
okay for you to go outside and stuff.
こうやって外出たりとかも
大丈夫だと思うんだよ
Also, you can go to school,
and... you know,
あと　ほら　学校行ったりとか
その　何つうか
it will let you do all sorts
of things a normal girl does.
普通の女の子がするようなこと
色々できるかもってさ
Furuya...
降谷君
えッ？
H-Hey...!
お　おい
What is it? Did I do something wrong here?
何だよ　何かまずかったか？　これ
Mm-mm, no, you didn't.
ううん　違うの
うん？
Furuya, you really are
thinking so much about me,
降谷君が
本当に私のこと思ってくれて
and I'm happy... but...
嬉しくて
でも…
...I just learned... that zombies
can't produce tears,
初めて知った
ゾンビって泣こうとしても
涙が出ないんですね
even when they want to cry.
Is that... right?
そう…　なんだ
Yes.
W-What?
何だよ
It's just, I thought that you
knew everything about zombies.
だって　ゾンビのことなら何でも
知ってるんだと思っていたから
So I was thinking, there are
some things not even Furuya knows.
だから　降谷君でも
知らないことがあるんだなって
Well, sure there are.
そりゃ　あるよ
I'll teach you all sorts of
things about zombies, okay?
色々教えてあげますね
ゾンビのこと
Rea...
礼弥
自由の身になった
つもりだろうが
...you may think you have gained freedom,
それは…
but it...
...is a counterfeit freedom!
偽りの自由！
Sure, you may have felt that
my upbringing has been strict,
確かにお前には　私のしつけが
厳しく感じられたのかもしれん
but if you think that running
away from it has given you freedom...
だが　そこから逃れることが
自由と思っているのなら
Nay!
否！
Now, come home, Rea.
さあ帰っておいで　礼弥
I will show you what true "freedom" is!
私が　真のフリーダムを教えよう
フッフフ
あッ　いけない
そろそろお食事しないと
Uh-oh. I need to eat soon.
Oh, I'll go get something for me to eat, too.
あ～　俺も何か食い物
買ってくっかな
I'll be right back.
Go ahead and start without me.
すぐに戻るから先に食ってろよ
ああ　うん
Ah, mm-hmm.
I do kind of miss eating meals a little.
お食事だけは　ちょっと寂しいな
I can't eat the same things that
Furuya does, after all.
降谷君と一緒のものが
食べられないから
でも　そこは仕方ないのかな
But I guess there's
nothing I can do about that.
I am a zombie,
and my guts are all torn up.
ゾンビなんだし
腸も壊れちゃってるし
Miss...
散華…
...Sanka Rea...
礼弥さん
Hi there!
おっは～
Oh, wow, what a coincidence!
Imagine, seeing you here!
ややあ　奇遇だな
こ～んなところで会えるなんて
フッ　運命か
It must be fate.
Who is that guy?
I don't know!
But whoever he is, we stand by for now!
All right.
Acknowledged.
Um... Er, who are you?
あの　えっと　あなたは？
何言ってんすか　以前
一緒に素敵なひとときを過ごした
What are you talking about?
I'm the one you spent that
fantastic moment with before, Yasutaka!
ヤ・ス・タ・カ
降谷のダチっすよ
I'm Furuya's friend.
Oh, the one from the school grounds.
校庭にいらっしゃった
Yeah! Are you doing some shopping later?
いや～　これから買い物っすか？
No, I'm already done shopping.
買い物は終わって
I see, then you have some leisure time, yes? Oh, yeah!
なるほど
What do we do?
Should we tell Master Dan'ichiro?
まったりタイムってやつっすね
なら　いいポイントがあるんす
No...
Let's watch a little while longer.
Then I know just the spot!
Come along, before you get too thirsty!
ささッ　舌の根の乾かぬうちに
Huh? U-Um...
あッ　あの
およ　礼弥さんって冷え性っすか？
腕がアイスみたいに冷たいな
Huh? Miss Rea,
do you have a cold constitution?
Your arm is as cold as ice.
I, uh...
私　あの…
でも大丈夫　超ホットな場所に
連れて行って差し上げてまいるぞ
But that's okay! I'm about
to take you to a super-hot place!
They're on the move!
You don't think they're on to us, do you?
Impossible... Who is that guy, anyway?
I don't know!
Never mind that, hurry after them!
ニューフフ　ニューフフ　ニュフフのフー
Um, where are we...
あの　どこまで…
えッ　外に出るんですか？
Huh? We're going outside?
That's right! Out in the bright
sunshine, where the two of us
そのとおり
うららかな光の中　二人で
will treat ourselves to
some leisure time, why don't we?
まったりタイムとシャレこみましょう
では　あ～りませんか
But I...
でも　私…
Oh, there's an open bench right there!
ちょうどベンチが空いてる
U-Um...
あッ　あの
私　あまり日中に外にいるのは…
I... don't care to be out in the sun...
Oh, no, no, you can't just
stay where there's air conditioning!
もうダメダメ
エアコンのとこばっかにいるのは
ほら　ここ眺めもいいっしょ
Look, the view is terrific here, isn't it?
Miss Rea, your fair complexion is beautiful,
色白の礼弥さんも美しいけど
不健康なのはいけないぞ
but you should look more healthy!
That boy is still there,
but this could be our chance.
あの男はいるが
今がチャンスかも
ちょうど
出口の近くにいるしな
She is right next to the exit.
- Come on, the first rays of summer
feel great! Let's go, quickly!
どうする　行くのか？
- What do we do? Do we go?
- Come on, the first rays of summer
feel great! Let's go, quickly!
さあさあ早く
All right, let's go. Execute!
よし行くぞ　決行だ
Let me take care of the boy!
あの男は　俺に任せろ
Keep the timing tight!
タイミングを合わせるぞ
Three...
３　２　１
Two...
One...
Go!
Huh?
あれ？
礼弥…
Rea...?
What kind of power is that?!
何だ　この力は
- Have her mental limiters really been undone?!
ホントに
脳のリミッターが外れてるのか
- No! Furuya!
- Have her mental limiters really been undone?!
降谷君
イヤ～
押さえきれん
I can't hold her!
Geez, where did she go?!
まったく　どこ行ったんだよ
キャ～ッ　助けて
Help me!
Rea...?
礼弥？
Rea!
礼弥！　どうした
What's wrong?!
No! Stay away!
イヤ～　来ないで　えい
え～っと　礼弥？
Uh... Rea...
イヤ～
ありがとう　助けにきてくれて
Thank you for coming to save me!
Er... I didn't really do anything...
And that bench...
いや　俺は何もやってないし
ていうか　ベンチ…
筋肉はそのまんまなんだから
腕　外れっぞ
Your muscles are still the same as ever.
You're gonna dislocate your arms.
I was so scared.
Those men tried to abduct me!
怖かったよ
あの人達が私をさらおうとして
クッ　大丈夫か？
Are you all right?
グハッ
ウッ…
ところで　あいつらは？
知らない
By the way, who are they?
I don't know.
And why is Yasutaka here?
つうか　何でヤスタカが？
W-We have no choice.
At this point, we have to change plans.
や　やむを得ん
こうなったら作戦変更だ
Hey, who are you folks?
Why did you come after Rea?
おい　おっさん達　何者だ
何で礼弥を狙った？
I'll call the police!
警察呼ぶぞ
Say something!
Why are you keeping quiet?!
何か言えよ　何黙ってんだ
You don't work for
the Sanka family, do you?
ひょっとして散華家の？
Behind you!
後ろ！
Wait!
待って　あッ
Miss... Sanka...
散華…　さん
もう
Geez...!
Furuya!
降谷く～ん！
申し訳ございません
I'm terribly sorry.
- Damn it! You guys let me go! Who are you?!
作戦を決行し　礼弥様を
捕まえようとしたのですが
- We executed the plan, and attempted
to catch Miss Rea, but...
- Damn it! You guys let me go! Who are you?!
誰なんだよ
その…
she had unbelievable power,
and we were unable to hold her,
信じられないような力で
押さえることができず
so we had no choice
but to switch to plan B.
やむなく作戦Ｂに変更しました
ふむ
Master Dan'ichiro,
what do you want us to do?
団一郎様　どうなさいますか
この男は捨てて
再度　礼弥様を…
Should we get rid of this boy,
and go after Miss Rea again?
No, keep him, and bring him to me.
いや　そのまま連れてこい
かしこまりました
As you wish.
Let's take this chance...
この際だ
...to make things clear to him, why don't we?
白黒つけようじゃないか
Right, Furuya?
なあ　降谷よ
Hitotsu dake kanau no nara
If I had just one wish
kimi no te no naka yureru chiisa na hana de itai
I would want to be a small flower, trembling in your hands
Hajimete miru mabushii kono sekai ga
Even if I become separated from you,
kimi to moshi hagureta to shite mo kitto
in this bright world I'm seeing for the first time,
mitsukedashite
I'm sure I'll find you
Mezametara soba ni iru yo
When I wake up, I'll stay beside you
ashita mo
tomorrow as well
Preview
Mero...?
萌路ちゃん
Oh, Mero...?
萌路ちゃんってば
Oh, well. Here goes... Next time...
しょうがない　いくよ
Next time on Sankarea,
episode 9: "A Mother's... Hand..."
"A Mother`s... Hand..."
Everybody watch mero!
みんな　見るメロ
Huh? Do it again?
I see. What are you gonna do?
えッ　とり直し？
そうですか　仕方ありませんな
蘭子殿が
入りを間違えましたからな
Lady Ranko missed her cue coming in.
Ugh, with a script as poor as this,
この程度の原稿でＮＧ出すのは
勘弁していただきたい
I wish you would refrain
from these bad takes.
萌路ちゃん…
Oh, Mero...